Guide to the George White Papers, 1932-1970 M1111
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
George White Papers
1932-1970
M1111
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
10.0 Linear feet (5 boxes, 1 carton, 4 flat boxes)
White, George
Biography
George White was born in Los Angeles June 22, 1908 to L. D. White, city manager of Alhambra. Graduating from Oregon State College in 1928, he worked as a reporter for five years on the San Francisco Bulletin and Los Angeles Daily News before entering the Mexican border patrol in 1933, transferring to the narcotics bureau the following year. In 1936 he infiltrated the notorious Hip Sing Tong brotherhood of Seattle by masquerading as a drug dealer. A simultaneous sting on both coasts based on information supplied by him destroyed the organization and led to over 30 arrests. ("When the Rookie took the Tong") He attained the rank of Colonel while serving in the Office of Strategic Services, where he helped to establish a school for counter-espionage. He commanded troops in India under to General "Wild Bill" Donovan during the allied invasion. In 1946 he led a drug bust in Mexico which cracked a dope ring led by Arthur Zweier. Travelling abroad in 1948 he traveled to France where he helped police capture a narcotics trafficker, Lucien Santoni, In Rome, he compiled evidence against heroin suppliers, resulting in the arrest of Marcello Enzi. In May 1948 he arrived in Istanbul, where he cracked a dope ring posing as a merchant seaman, aiding Turkish police in capturing smugglers led by Severt Dalgakiran, and in the seizure of heroin plant. ("The Calculating Colonel and the Turkish Trap") He was awarded the Treasury medal for exceptional service in recognition of his efforts in destroying dope rings in the Middle East and Europe. Later he was assigned to New England. He was appointed head of the Chicago Narcotics Bureau and was sent to Mexico City in 1949 where he uncovered a Mexican heroin smuggling operation that was headed by Francisco Lavat. Appointed director of the Bureau of Narcotics in San Francisco, he uncovered a drug ring in Oakland run by Andrew Ingoglia ("Undercover Trap"). He was assigned to Boston, when he was tapped as a special investigator to Kefauver hearings into tax fraud and racketeering His testimony against renowned gangster Lucky Luciano led to his deportation. He was then assigned as chief investigator to Newbold Morris whose committee was investigating graft and corruption in government agencies. His refusal to reveal his sources for information given in testimony before the Senate led to his imprisonment overnight. In 1954, White was called to investigate corruption in the Houston Police department, the ensuing shake-up ended in the death of an officer turned informant and the ensuing dismissal of the Police Chief Morrison who was found to be an addict, and a re-structuring of the entire department. ("Dope-buster") In 1955, back in San Francisco, White conducted a sting operation, which exposed the state narcotic agent Braumoeller of selling drugs seized in raids to known criminals, resulting in his arrest. In 1956, he championed the cause of convicted schoolteacher Robert Enzensperger, who was falsely accused of transporting marijuana. His investigation led to the release and exoneration of the teacher.( "The Strange Case of the Framed Schoolteacher") He spearheaded a heroin seizure in San Francisco sending Rinaldo (Red) Ferrari to jail for narcotics trafficking in 1956.("When they Stole for Junk"). As the culture became more permissive, White continued to speak out against the use of marijuana. Testifying before a senate sub-committee in 1959, he advocated greater cooperation with the Mexican authorities and stiffer penalties for drug offenders In 1965 George White retired to Stinson Beach where he soon took a post as Chief of the fire department.
Provenance
Gift of Perham Foundation, 2000
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
- Series 1. Papers and Correspondence
  - Working reports - Chicago, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Touhy kidnapping, November 10 & 11th, 1932; 5pp. (carbons)
    - Mc G bombing, November 11 - 13th, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Attempts to reach Courtney, November 15 & 16th, 1932; 2pp. (carbons)
    - Recent threatened gang war, November 10 & 11th, 1932; 5pp. (carbons)
    - Melrose Park, November 17 & 18th, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Melrose Park, November 19 - 20th, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Melrose Park, Murder at Polly Rue roadhouse, November 22 & 23rd, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Georgie Nielson, November 24 & 25th, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Hymie Levine, November 26 - 28th, 1932; 6pp. (carbons)
    - Murder of Maxie Williams (alias Max Tenler), November 29 & 30th, 1932; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Police Officers / Prostitution & solicitation in the open, December 1st & 2nd, 1932; 6pp. (carbons)
  - Louis Adelman, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Statement given by Louis Adelman Re: investigation of Emanuel Weiss, 32pp.
  - Santora and Petrelli investigations, 1940/ 41 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Case report - Helmuth Hartman, et al, 12 typed pp., carbons
    - Statement - Helmuth Hartman, et al, 8 typed pp., carbons - 5 copies
    - Conspiracy charges against Salvatore Santora et al, April 27, 1940; 14 typed pp. - carbons
  - OSS (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: officers and training
    - Letters
    - TLS, January 2, 1941 to Major Garland Williams from Ernest M. Gentry on Treasury Department stationary, re: Santora and Petrelli investigations, 13 typed pp. (carbons)
    - December 27, 1941 to Major Garland Williams re: Santora and Petrelli investigations Signed Ernest M. Gentry, 53 typed pp. w/ holograph notations
  - Foreign Assignments: India, 1944/45 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: narcotics in near east, October 15, 1943; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: C.H. Ellis, February 2, 1944; 1p. (carbons)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Gerald Close re: GW, May 3, 1944; 1p. (copy)
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: narcotics in India, May 19, 1944; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: narcotic smuggling in the near east, April 19, 1944; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: narcotics in India, October 30, 1944; 9p (carbons) w/ encl to Major McDonough, 3pp. (carbons) stamped "secret"
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger GW re: seizure of opium on SS Teucer, February 6, 1945; 4pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from F. Thorton re: seizure of opium on SS Teucer, February 6, 1945; 4pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: conference, March 2, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to James Murphy from H. J. Anslinger re: reward to informer, March 3, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: reward to informer, March 3, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: war department policy, March 9, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Joseph P. McCarthy re: seizure of opium on SS Teucer, March 26, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: reward to informer, April 12, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Garland Williams re: investigative agent, April 27, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium seizure on SS Chung Shan, October 1, 1945; 1p (carbons)
    - TLS to Commissioner of Customs from A. F. Scharff re: opium seizure on SS Chung Shan, October 2, 1945; 1p (carbons)
    - TLS to Lt. Col. John Murray from H. J. Anslinger re: investigative agent, October 26, 1945; 1p.
    - TLS to Lt. Col. John Murray from H. J. Anslinger re: narcotics in India, November 6, 1946; 3p (carbon)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Lt. Col. John Murray re: narcotics in India, December 5, 1945; 1p (carbon)
    - TLS to Lt. Col. John Murray from H. J. Anslinger re: opium seizures, December 19, 1946; 1p (carbon)
  - Zweier bust, October - November 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Foreign assignments - Istanbul, Turkey, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Istanbul, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium in Iran, January 6, 1943; 3pp. (carbons) w/copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium in Iran, May 1, 1948; 3pp. (carbons) - extensive holograph notes on back - w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium harvest, May 9, 1948; 3pp. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium harvest, May 11, 1948; 2pp. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium purchase, May13, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium sales, May 19, 1948; 1p. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium harvest, May 28, 1948; 2pp. (carbons) - holograph notes on back - w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Taranto family, June 2, 1948; 1p. (photocopies) w/ copy
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium seizure, June 4, 1948; 1p. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Taranto family, June 5, 1948; 1p. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to Garland Williams from Will Wood re: Ivan and Katina Dodig, June 8, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams re: Ivan and Katina Dodig, June 10, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams re: Ivan and Katina Dodig, June 10, 1948; 2pp. (carbon)
    - Report by Charles Siragusa re: Ivan and Katina Dodig, June 10, 1948; 5pp. (carbons)
    - June 10, 1948, 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to GW from Garland Williams, Tehran, Iran re: situation, January 22, 1949; 2pp.
    - ALS to GW from Bogan Nadi, Athens, Greece, 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Ivar T. Saunders from Istanbul Turkey re: opium sales, July 13, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to Garland Williams from Will Wood re: Ivan and Katina Dodig, June 15, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to Mr. Morlock from H. J. Anslinger, June 17, 1948; 1p. (carbon) w/ reports, 1p.(carbons)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Marseille - The Santoni Smugglers, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Italy - the Enzi syndicate, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Istanbul - Sevket Dalgakiran, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Istanbul, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: synthetic cocaine, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Announcement from Associated Press re: seizure of Heroin, June 5,1948; 1p. w/ photo
    - Summaries of correspondence, to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: narcotics situation in the near east, January/ February 1949; 11pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Rome, Italy re: Picadilly bar, March 31, 1949; 1p. (carbon)
    - Announcement from Istanbul re: seizure of Heroin factory, November 30,1949; 2p.
    - TLS to GW from David Murad on Couri, Murad, & Co. stationary, re: price for goods, September 23, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Garland Williams re: Ankara, February, 1950; 1p.
    - Announcement from Istanbul re: discovery of Heroin factory, March 9, 1950; 1p.
    - Announcement from Istanbul re: seizure of Heroin factory, March 31, 1950; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Garland Williams, May 1, 1950; 1p. w/ 4 photos
    - TLS to J. W. Bulkey from M. L. Harney re: Heroin seizure, April 18, 1950; 1p. (carbon)
    - Telegram to Secretary of State from Ankara re: Heroin seizure, April 11, 1950 (carbon)
    - To Mr. Olgun from H. J. Anslinger re: police cooperation, April 18, 1950; 2pp. (carbons)
    - Memo from H. J. Anslinger re: recommendation of GW for service award, 3pp. (carbons)
    - Article "The Calculating Colonel and the Turkish Trap", True Magazine, January 1960; (photocopy)
    - Newsclippings
  - Foreign assignments - Marseilles, France, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Marseille - The Santoni Smugglers, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Holograph note on Lucien Santoni
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: proposed moves in Europe, June 17, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: Investigations in Turkey, June 3, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Istanbul activities, June 10, 1948; 8pp. (carbons) - w/ photos taped on reverse - w/ copy
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: opium seizure, June 26, 1948; 6pp. (carbons) - w/ photos taped on reverse - w/ copies
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: synthetic cocaine, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - TLS to William Canup from H. J. Anslinger re: synthetic cocaine, September 21, 1948
    - TLS to GW from Bill re: Santoni case, October 21, 1948; 3pp. w/clippings
    - TLS to GW from Marseille (in French), December 26, 1948; 1p.
  - Foreign assignments - Rome, 1taly, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Typed report on foreign assignment re: Italy - the Enzi syndicate, August 25, 1948; 1p. (carbon)
    - Confidential report on Marcello Heinzinger alias Enzi
    - Memo to H.J. Anslinger from GW re: heroin purchase, July 2, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to Cecil Gray from GW re: thanks, July 2, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Cecil Gray re: thanks, July 6, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to Guiseppi Dosi from Will Wood, re: thanks, September 30, 1948; 1p.
    - Memo to GW from H.J. Anslinger re: Nicholas DiMarzo, July 13, 1948; 1p.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams re: Nicholas Dimarzo, July 12, 1948; 2pp. (carbons)w/ criminal record and case file, 4pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Il Capo from Rome, Italy re: GW, July 24, 1948; 1p.
    - Telegram from H. J. Anslinger to GW re: record of Nicholas Di Marzo, July 7, 1948; 2pp. w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Nicholas Di Marzo, July, 1948; 2pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Nicholas Di Marzo, July 8, 1948; 2pp. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: Manfredi, July 23, 1948; 2pp. (carbons) w/ copies
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: heroin arrest, August 3, 1948; 1p. (carbons) w/ copies
  - Foreign assignments - Mexico, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - TLS to Francisco de la Vega from H. J. Anslinger re: Francisco Lavat, November 17, 1948; 5pp. (carbons) w/ mug shots, identity card (copy)
    - TLS to GW from Manuel Miranda(in Spanish), August 7, 1949; 1p. w/ 2 photos
    - GW case file on Mexico bust, 19pp. (carbons)
    - newsclippings
  - Cairo, Egypt, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Summaries of correspondence, to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: narcotics situation in the near east, January/ February 1949; 11pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: opium growing in Iran, January 26, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy) w/ press clippings, 10pp.
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: opium growing in Iran, January 26, 1949; 4p. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: Narcotic legislation in Iran, February 8, 1949; 4pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: Narcotic legislation in Iran, February 8, 1949; 4pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: opium traffic in Iran, February 8, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Bagdad, Iran re: Opium exports from Iran, February 8, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: opium situation, February 17, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: Hashish traffic in Lebanon, February 17, 1949; 6pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: narcotic expert, February 18, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: world prices for opium, February 18, 1949; 2pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: opium production agreements, February 21, 1949; 3pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: delegates, February 21, 1949; 2pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Ankara, Turkey re: Narcotic traffic, February 21, 1949; 2pp. (Photocopy)
    - Note to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: Swinburne quote, March 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - Note re: Williams, March 1949; 1p. (Photocopy) w/ newsclipping
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Istanbul, Turkey re: poppy seeds, March 5, 1949; 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Athens, Greece re: opium cultivation, March 8, 1949; 3pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Athens, Greece re: Gustav source, March 12, 1949; 8pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Athens, Greece re: opium control, March 10, 1949; 8pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Salonika, Greece re: Voutsinas brothers, March 16, 1949; 2pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Salonika, Greece re: smugglers list, March 16, 1949; 2pp. (Photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Salonika, Greece re: Bulgaria connection, March 17, , 1949; , 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Cairo, Egypt re: Mr. Russell, , March 25, 1949; , 2pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Cairo, Egypt re: Egyptian delegate, , March 28, 1949; , 3pp. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Rome, Italy re: Picadilly bar, , March 31, 1949; , 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Rome, Italy re: agency in Egypt, , March 31, 1949; , 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Naples, Italy re: Lucky Luciano, , April 8, 1949; , 1p. (Photocopy)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Garland Williams from Trieste re; Narcotic traffic, , April 25, 1949; , 2pp. (Photocopies)
  - Service award, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Exceptional civilian service award, (photocopy)
    - Press release
    - Letters of congratulation
    - Articles re: receipt of award
  - Billie Holiday, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Articles RE: drug bust of Billie Holiday by GW
    - TLS to GW from H. J. Anslinger re: analyzing agents, , March 4, 1949; , 1p. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from GW re: defending actions, , February 10, 1949; , 1p. (photocopy)
  - Conversation, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Transcription of a conversation between Albert Benevedes & Hugh Bascom, , April 25, 1950; , 60pp. (mimeo copies)
  - Benedict Pocoroba, Overseas reports (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , June 13, 1950; , 1p. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , June 23, 1950; , 2pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , June 30, 1950; , 2pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , July 6, 1950; , 1p. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , August 3, 1950; , 3pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , August 10, 1950; , 2pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to H. J. Anslinger from Benedict Pocoroba re: Lucky Luciano, , August 20, 1950; , 2pp. (photocopies)
  - Warrren Olney III, Correspondence, 1950 - 54 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III, , October 30, 1950; , 1p.
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW, re: relationship between bureau and Attorney General's Office, , January 10, 1952; , 2 pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III on Special Crime Study Commission on Organized Crime stationary, re:Willie Moretti, , October 30, 1950; , 2p.
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW on Bureau of Narcotics stationary, re: Willie Moretti, , November 24, 1952; , 4 pp. (carbons)
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III, , January 9, 1953; , 1p.
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III, , January 12, 1953; , 1p.
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW re: Max Goldschien, , January 12, 1953; , 1p. (carbons)
    - Memo from GW to H. J. Anslinger, re: National Central Telephone Index, , July 10, 1953; , 4pp. (photocopies)
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW on Bureau of Narcotics stationary, re: National Central Telephone Index, , September 1, 1953; , 4 pp. (carbons)
    - Memo from GW to Warren Olney III re: Julius Rolnitsky, , September 15, 1953; , 1p.w/ newsclipping
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW re: Sebastiano Nani, , December 23, 1953; , 1p. (carbons)
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III on Department of Justice stationary, re: Sebastiano Nani, , January 12, 1954; , 2p.
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW re: Sebastiano Nani, , April 22, 1954; , 2p. (carbons)
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from GW re: return to San Francisco, , March 10, 1955; , 1p. (photocopy)
    - TLS to Warren Olney III from Virgil Peterson re: contracts on Peterson & White, December 5, 1955; 2pp. (photocopies)
    - William Burkett from GW re: recommendation, February 1, 1952; 2pp.
    - TLS to GW from Warren Olney III re: John M. Petrone, July 22, 1955; 2pp.
    - Newsclippings
    - Photocopies of 2 articles on Warren Olney III
  - Kefauver (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - United States Senate Special Committee to Investigate Crime in Interstate Commerce
    - Letterhead stationary
    - Senate District Crime Investigating Committee Questionnaire
  - Zamloch, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Transcript trial proceedings against Archer Zamloch, August 29, 1950; 1pp. (carbons - 2 copies
    - TLS to GW from J. Waties Waring on U S District Court stationary re: Zamloch case, May 4, 1951; 1p
    - TLS to GW from J. Waties Waring on U S District Court stationary re: Zamloch case, May 24, 1951; 1p
    - TLS to GW from J. Waties Waring on U S District Court stationary re: Zamloch case, November 7, 1950; 2pp (photocopies)
  - Gaetano Luchese, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles, correspondence and reports Gaetano Luchese on alias "Three-finger Brown"
  - Newbold Morris (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Articles, agency documents reports and articles re: Newbold Morris
  - Newbold Morris (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Articles, agency documents reports and articles re: Newbold Morris
  - Rosaro Pisciotta, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Statement by Rosario Pisciotta, April 8, 1953; 4pp. (carbons)
    - Report re: Louis Taylor & Joseph Sumpter, June 20, 1952; 1p. (carbons)
    - Memo re: Interview w/ U. S. Attorney Myles Law by GW, June 19, 1952; 7pp. (original w/ carbon copy)
    - Deposition before Notary re: Interview w/ U. S. Attorney Myles Law, May 20, 1952; 3pp. (carbons)
    - Press release by Harry Truman re: appointment of Newbold Morris, February 14, 1952; 1p. (carbons)
    - Press release by Harry Truman re: executive order announcing appointment of Newbold Morris, February 20, 1952; 1p. (carbons)
    - Affadavit of Rosario Pisciotta changing plea, December 7, 1951; 2pp. (copy)
    - Memo from GW to Newbold Morris, April 2, 1952 re: Rosario Pisciotta Narcotic Case Report on Anthony and Rosaro Pisciotta by Arthur J. Guiliani, December 21, 1950; 12 typed pp.
    - Memo from GW to Newbold Morris re: change of plea by Rosaro Pisciotta, 3 typed pp. (carbons)
    - Investigation report by George H. Gaffney on search for Rosaro Pisciotta, December 31, 1950; 4 typed pp. (carbons)
    - Signed Statement by George M. Belk re: drug seizure, December 17, 1950; 1p.
    - Signed Statement by George M. Belk re: drug purchase, October 23 & 24, 1950; 2pp.